We will come to the RDP remote desktop protocol.
This is one of the service in Microsoft Windows that usually the detectors will be using
this protocol for laterally moved from one machine to another machine.
I do not want to duplicate this video and command and control RDP the next section you
can see X RDP that video both are same both the RDP protocol used for both the things
the lateral movement as well as the command and control so I do not want to duplicate
this I just created the video in this section to enable the RDP and we need to do few
more things we need to modify the firewall rule as well as we need to add the user into
the remote desktop thing.
So basically we need to enable the RDP in the target machine because most of the environment
will be configured with RDP some of the environment they will not configure or configure
RDP at that time we need to enable the RDP in the target machine.
So RDP is nothing but a remote desktop protocol so we can do a lateral movement and
command and control with this we can see this in the practical way how to do that let
modify the registry keys first ok. So this is the registry T we need to modify to enable the
RDP connections on the post to setting the F10ETS connections to 0 we are enabling the RDP ok.
So once we enable the RDP in the machine the R good to use RDP in this machine ok the
threat actors will enable RDP in all the machines inside the organization by using some
kind of back file or some other BBS or some executables ok.
So let us hop off from this video and we will continue our discussion in the next video
see you bye bye.